Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
It may have been her own inexperience
that caused the tragic incident.
However, the young life lost
on the battlefield...
...was not a small misfortune.
Nobody could hope to comfort
the grief-stricken Kai Shiden.
The White Base was now above
the South American continent...
...on its way to Jaburo, the
Federation Forces headquarters.
Tragedy in Jaburo
There's no mistaking it.
The Trojan Horse is headed for Jaburo.
Just as our spy reported. Don't lose them.
Yes sir!
Wow!
Butterfly! Butterfly! Butterfly!
Butter... fly! Butterfly!
They're so beautiful...
Amazing!
So, we've finally made it
to the Federation Forces' dock.
Don't like it?
I'm fine.
Attention all hands!
We're entering Jaburo.
Keep watching for any enemy aircraft.
He said we're entering Jaburo,
but I don't see anything.
Hey. Look!
Landing completed, sir.
The Trojan Horse's signal disappeared!
That means we've finally located
the biggest entrance to Jaburo.
Conduct a thorough search of the area
where the Trojan Horse disappeared.
We'll crush the ship and the Jaburo base!
The damage is quite extensive.
Worse than what they reported.
Well, the White Base has certainly seen
a lot of heavy combat...
Right! Commence inspection!
Commence inspection procedures!
First and second teams,
prepare for inspection!
You must be Captain Woody...
I'm Bright Noa,
chief officer of the White Base.
Well done.
Is there a young man here
named Amuro Ray?
Yes, sir. Amuro.
Yes?
He's Amuro?!
Yes, sir.
I never expected somebody so young.
What did you want, sir?
You're the pilot of the Gundam?
Yes, sir.
Matilda told me a lot about you, but...
Ms. Matilda told you...?
And what is it?
They called it a Zock. Mobile Suit Zock.
Can we use it?
It's amphibious, with a jumping capability
several times that of a Zaku.
Says who?
The engineers at North America's California Base.
I see.
So that's it there.
I hope it isn't just for show.
As soon as the reinforcements arrive from the California Base we'll send our second attack team.
You'll go as an advance party, so carry out
your mission to the best of your abilities.
Thank you very much.
I never expected a physical examination
to be such a chore.
You said it.
But Amuro, your exam was especially long.
Was there something wrong?
No way. They were all busy checking
brain waves and taking x-rays and stuff...
Same with you, right?
Mr. Kai!
They told me I'm physically healthy
and mentally sound.
This medical facility is perfectly
furnished with everything imaginable.
There's nothing wrong with us!
Don't wanna! No!
Katz, Letz, please keep it down!
What's wrong with these bodies? Nothing!
Yeah, that's right, that's right!
Looks like you don't have any cavities.
Sir.
Thanks.
Captain Woody.
Oh, Amuro.
Aren't you going to get some rest, sir?
Supervision is a thankless job.
Can I do anything to help out?
As long as you're at Jaburo,
you can relax and leave it all to us.
I-I'm sorry, sir...
Captain. Did you know Lt. Matilda well?
After Operation Odessa was over
we were planning to get married.
Get married?
We expected that the White Base
would arrive at Jaburo in time...
...so Matilda had hoped to have
the crew attend our wedding.
l-ls that so...
I had no idea...
I... I'm sorry, Captain Woody.
If I'd only known how to use
the Gundam better...
...then Ms. Matilda wouldn't have died.
I'm so sorry.
Don't be so conceited, Amuro!
Huh?
The Gundam alone can't win the war,
nor could it have saved Matilda.
It's not that simple.
B-But...
If a pilot fights as best he can in each battle...
...and doesn't do anything
that he'd later regret, that's enough.
Yes, sir.
I love the White Base because I know
Matilda cared so much about this ship.
That's why I'm doing my best
to get it fully repaired.
Yes, sir.
Both of us are doing our duty.
I found it. The main entrance to Jaburo.
If I hadn't got a metallic reaction,
I would have missed it.
That means they'd never
launch an attack here.
They wouldn't want anyone
to see through the camouflage.
In conclusion, the White Base corps
shall continue their mission as before.
Yes, sir.
Now, you will be assigned to the Tianem fleet...
...but official notice will only be given just before the operation.
Yes, sir. What should we do in the meantime?
Rest up in your assigned quarters.
Also, you will not be penalized.
Ms. Mirai, please consider it as
our repaying a favor to your father.
My father?
To this day, we regret the Federation's loss
of such a valuable politician.
If your father were alive today,
you wouldn't have had to emigrate to Side 7.
Please, sir, I would rather not discuss it.
The alarm!
Enemy approaching hatches 231 and 243
of the South Block!
Take level 2 battle stations!
Another patrol?
Well, you may return to your quarters.
Go to alert status, just in case.
Yes, sir!
Don't worry about it, Lt. Commander.
But I must apologize for bringing a force
that's too small for a first-wave attack.
It's no problem.
How long until we reach Jaburo, Lt. Commander?
Less than an hour.
Excellent.
Should we attack?
No, that'd reveal our location. Hold off.
Two are Goggs, for underwater combat.
The other one isn't in the computer.
A new model of mobile suit?
Attention all units in Jaburo's South Block!
Go to level 2 battle stations!
I'm going ahead.
Okay!
Do it.
Right.
Where are you going?
The White Base!
Everyone's taking level 2 battle stations,
so where else are we going to go?
The others are coming as well.
Yes. That makes sense.
How many went up?
I'm not sure, but there were at least four.
Only one is authentic.
The others are for camouflage.
They're coming!
Switch to level 1 battle stations!
Signal flare confirmed at bearing 128.
Fire missiles!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Captain! We've been ordered
to take level 1 battle stations!
I'm getting the crew aboard the White Base!
All right! Go ahead.
We've finished repairs on the mobile suits
but the White Base itself isn't operational.
Fraw Bow, Mirai! Get intel from
General HQ as quickly as you can!
We can't make a move until
we know what's going on out there!
Yes, this is White Base.
General HQ, how is the enemy deployed?
Can we launch?
Sir! We can guard the entrance to Jaburo...
We'll send Amuro and Sayla in the G-Bull.
Roger that! Send out Kai and Hayato
in the Guncannon and Guntank! Hurry!
I can't believe those Zeons
followed us all the way out here!
Miharu. I won't mope about any longer.
I'll totally crush Zeon, so people
won't have to suffer like you anymore!
Guntank, Hayato, rolling out!
Amuro! Ready?
Go ahead!
G-Bull, Sayla and Amuro, launching!
Ms. Sayla! Let's stay close to
Jaburo's entranceway.
The enemy will try to force their way in.
Roger that.
Huh... Gundams?
No. Those are GMs,
the Gundam's mass-production type.
First wave of Zakus,
Goufs and Doms going in.
Captain Char,
please launch your Z'Gok team last.
Roger, Lt. Commander.
Li Hwan! Jittal! Let's go!
Stay close to me.
Yes, sir!
We've already lost Li Hwan!
Jaburo is well defended.
How many mobile suits will land safely?
No! J-Jittal, too?!
It's vital that I join up with the advance party.
It looks like 28 mobile suits have landed.
That's quite a large force.
Yes. But I believe it's still too small
to fight against all of Jaburo.
They're only targeting A Block
where the spaceship dock is located.
The White Base must have been followed.
Right.
Perhaps the White Base will always be
a nuisance to the rest of us.
We still haven't heard anything
at all from General HQ, sir.
Switch all monitors over
to external surveillance!
We can't fight like this.
General HQ will hear from me later!
What a situation...
If we carelessly go outside, that will
give away the location of Jaburo's entrance.
At this rate...
We have no idea what the enemy is doing,
so there's no way for us to fight them.
If we moved out and found the enemy
in front of us, we'd be toast.
I can't even avenge Miharu, can I?!
They're coming... Damn Zeon.
Hm? There they are.
Boraskyniv. How are things proceeding?
Sir! We just finished setting the explosives.
Should we break in now?
Not yet. Are we going from the front?
Yes, sir.
Any other entrances?
There's a smaller entrance...
...about 500 meters upstream.
Hm... We'll attack both at the same time.
The two Goggs will breach this entrance.
Boraskyniv and I will break through
the one upstream. Follow me!
They're here!
Th-They're here! It's Zeon!
They allowed Zeon to break through?!
How could they...?!
Workers, join the defense!
Sir!
Matilda sacrificed her life
to protect the White Base...
There's no way that I'll let it be destroyed.
I won't let you get close to the White Base!
Don't underestimate me!
One Gogg destroyed!
Kai took it out!
Ms. Sayla! The G-Bull must turn back!
What?
The enemy broke through another entrance.
Let's leave the rest to Mr. Kai and Hayato.
Roger that!
It seems many have broken through, Amuro.
Zeon scum!
That's our White Base you're attacking!
Fraw Bow! Instruct the G-Bull
to change to the Gundam!
Enemy mobile suits are advancing quickly!
Y-Yes, sir!
G-Bull! G-Bull!
Please Convert to Gundam!
Roger! What's invading?
Are they Zakus? Or Goufs?
We don't know!
B Deck! Please send out G-Armor's B-Parts.
The enemy...?
A hovercraft is no use here! Please fall back!
What? That's Captain Woody!
Captain! Don't do it!
F-Fall back now, please!
A red mobile suit?
It's not a Zaku.
But could the red mobile suit mean...
...that Char's here?!
A GM!
Stop! Don't close in carelessly!
It's so fast!
There's no mistake... It's him...
He's come back to fight us.
I'm sure of it... That's Char!
Is it you, Char?!
You've gotten even better, Gundam!
He's good.
Damn Zeon!
Get out of Jaburo!
Captain Woody! You can't!
You must be joking!
Captain!
Captain Woody...!
Char! Hold it!
The main camera has been damaged!
Boraskyniv! Do you read me?!
I need some backup now!
Don't get in my way.
I'm taking out Char!
There!
There's no mistake...
That mobile suit... I'm certain it was Char.
So Char has pursued us
all the way to Jaburo...
Amuro! Do you read me? Are you all right?
I'm okay.
But I let one mobile suit escape.
You did very well.
We destroyed most of the enemy force.
But they did a lot of damage.
I'm not surprised.
Captain Woody was a casualty...?
Yes, sir.
He must have cared about the White Base
even more than we do...
...That's how it seemed to me.
Yes, I understand.
Men can feel emotion so strongly sometimes.
Is that true?
Uh...
Oh... And Char's back.
Char? Did you see him?
No. I only saw a red mobile suit...
...but I'm positive that it was Char, the Red Comet.
Who would ever call Katz, Letz and Kikka
"nothing but a nuisance"?
And who will find the enemy's time bombs
in time to save Jaburo?!
Meanwhile, Char and Sayla meet...
for the second time.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
A Wish of War Orphans.
Next Time
A Wish of War Orphans
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...